Guide to the Mathew B. Brady and Levin Corbin Handy Photographic Studios Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Collected Photographs and Artifacts, circa 1840-circa 1940; Series IV; (23 boxes)
  - Mechanical Prints, (39 mechanical prints)
    - Engravings
      - Georgia, Whitfield County. Battle of Rocky Face Ridge, after a painting by Alonzo Chappel published by Johnson, Fry & Co., 1864 (Box 68, Folder 3161)
      - Maryland, Frederick. Arrival of Abraham Lincoln's train at the Station, sketched by Hamilton in Harper's Weekly, 1862 Oct 25 (Box 68, Folder 3162)
      - Massachusetts, Middlesex County. British Retreat from Concord, based on a painting by Alonzo Chappel published by Johnson, Fry & Co., 1874 (Box 68, Folder 3163)
      - New York, West Point. landing of George Washington at West Point (Box 68, Folder 3164)
      - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia. Signing the Declaration of Independence after a painting by John Trumbull (Box 68, Folder 3165)
      - Portraits
        - John Caldwell Calhoun (Box 68, Folder 3166)
        - Jefferson Davis (Box 68, Folder 3167)
        - Abraham Lincoln from Frank Moore, Rebellion Record, a Diary of American Events, 1864 (Box 68, Folder 3168)
        - Abraham Lincoln and members of his cabinet, O.D. Case & Co., 1864 (Box 68, Folder 3169)
        - Abraham Lincoln after a painting by Alonzo Chappel published by Johnson, Fry, & Co., 1870 (Box 68, Folder 3170)
        - Abraham Lincoln by T. Johnson after a photograph by Alexander Hesler from The Century, Volume 33, Issue 1, 1886 Nov (Box 68, Folder 3171)
        - William Henry Moody with an inscription and autograph, 1904 Dec 1 (Box 68, Folder 3172)
        - Moses with angels viewing the Promised Land from frontispiece of a Bible and an index page (Box 68, Folder 3173)
        - Federal Leaders of the Civil War (Box 68, Folder 3174)
        - Officers of the 37th Tennessee Infantry, Confederate States of America (Box 68, Folder 3175)
    - Etchings
      - Pennsylvania. Valley Forge. House that served as the headquarters of George Washington (Box 68, Folder 3176)
      - Portraits
        - Abraham Lincoln by H. B. Hall from an engraving by Marshall (Box 68, Folder 3177)
        - Bernhardt Wall, 1939 (Box 68, Folder 3178)
    - Halftones
      - District of Columbia, Washington. 4 1/2 Street NW and Pennsylvania Avenue NW, southeast corner (Box 68, Folder 3179)
      - Illinois, Chicago. Statue of Abraham Lincoln sculpted by Augustus Saint-Gaudens, published by the John Lane Company (Box 68, Folder 3180)
      - New Jersey, Newark. Osborn H. Oldroyd standing by a statue of Abraham Lincoln sculpted by Gutzon Borglum (Box 68, Folder 3181)
      - Portraits
        - Abraham Lincoln by Francis Bicknell Carpenter (Box 68, Folder 3182)
        - Abraham Lincoln, portraits from The Poets' Lincoln; Tributes in Verse to the Martyred President," by Osborn H Oldroyd, 1915 (Box 68, Folder 3183)
        - Leonidas Polk, Confederate States of America (Box 68, Folder 3184)
      - Identification key to individuals in the mural Summer Mural by Charles Hoffbauer, part of the Four Seasons of the Confederacy murals at the Battle Abbey, Richmond, Virginia (Box 68, Folder 3185)
    - Lithographs
      - District of Columbia, Washington. United States General Post Office, circa 1860 (Box 68, Folder 3186)
      - North Carolina, Durham, Vicinity. William Tecumseh Sherman and Joseph Eggleston Johnston at the Bennett Place (Box 68, Folder 3187)
  - Magic Lanterns, (3 transparencies)
    This subseries consists of hand-colored glass transparencies in wooden frames.
    - Jesus and the feeding the multitude (Box 69, Folder 3188)
    - Removal of Jesus from the cross (Box 69, Folder 3189)
    - Glass VII. History of the United States. 80. First Prayer of Congress in Carpenters' Hall, Philadelphia, Sep 1774 (Box 69, Folder 3190)
  - Ephemera, (16 items)
    This subseries consists of a variety of ephemera related to operation of the photography studios and life in Washington, District of Columbia.
    - Business Card. Robert T. Hoy (Box 70, Folder 3191)
    - Calling Cards. Mrs. William M. Abbey (Box 70, Folder 3192)
    - Envelope. L. C. Handy, Photographer, printed envelope (Box 70, Folder 3193)
    - Ferry Schedule. Virginia Ferry Corporation, Cape Charles - Little Creek (Norfolk) (Box 70, Folder 3194)
    - Letterhead of Frederick Cox (Box 70, Folder 3195)
    - Glass Negative Boxes
      - Eastman Kodak Company
        - Eastman Lantern Slide Plates (Box 70, Folder 3196)
        - Wratten & Wainwright Panchromatic Dry Plates (Box 70, Folder 3197)
      - G. Cramer Dry Plate Company, Cramer's Photo Dry Plates (Box 70, Folder 3198)
      - Hammer Dry Plate Company
        - Hammer Lantern Plates (Box 70, Folder 3199-3200)
        - Photographic Dry Plates (Box 70, Folder 3201-3203)
      - M. A. Seed Dry Plate Company
        - Extra Rapid Double-Coated Nonhalation Dry Plates (Box 70, Folder 3204)
        - Extra Rapid Dry Plates (Box 70, Folder 3205)
    - Lantern Slide Mats. Burke and James, The Ideal Lantern Slide Mats (Box 70, Folder 3206)
  - Oversize Collected Photographs, (13 photographic prints)
    - Abel, Joseph, P. H. Cass, Estelle G. Mozart, and William A. Miller
      - Multiple images, consisting of people ice skating upon a frozen waterway; views of waterways; view of cattle in a river; a cow among rushes; and a view of a mill, (6 photographic prints) (Box 71, Folder 3207)
    - Gessford
      Studio at 373 Fifth Avenue, New York, New York
      - Studio portrait of a man (Box 71, Folder 3208)
    - Miller, William A.
      - Multiple images, consisting of a hay wagon and a threshing crew, (2 photographic prints) (Box 71, Folder 3209)
    - Parker, Charles
      Studio at 477 Pennsylvania Avenue NW, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Studio portrait of Benjamin Harrison, Panel photograph, 29.1 X 42.8 cm. (Box 71, Folder 3210)
    - Price, George
      - Copy photograph of a portrait painting of Abraham Lincoln by George W. F. Travis (Box 71, Folder 3211)
    - Thompson, E. B.
      - Multiple images, consisting of a cannon at Indian Head, Maryland; as well as the house boat, Judge Stake, possibly on the Potomac River, (2 photographic prints) (Box 71, Folder 3212)
  - Oversize Mechanical Prints
    - Engraving by Holcomb that depicts Chief Justice Taney administering the oath of office to James Buchanan from an ambrotype by Mathew B. Brady, from Frank Leslie's Magazine, 1857 Mar 14 (Box 71, Folder 3213)
    - Lithograph of the 4th Tennessee Cavalry, Confederate States of America. Includes Baxter Smith, Paul F. Anderson, W. S. Bledsoe, and George B. Guild (Box 71, Folder 3214)
  - Artifacts
    Arranged alphabetically by the general name of the artifact
    - Bell (Box 72, Folder 3215)
    - Eyeglasses (Box 72, Folder 3216)
    - Ink well with two rotating glass wells (Box 72, Folder 3217)
    - Lapel pins from the Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association (Box 72, Folder 3218)
    - Lens
      Arranged from shortest to longest focal length
      - Poco shutter assembly (patented May 22, 1894) with a Turner-Reich Anistigmat 7 1/4 in. (patented May 14, 1895) mounted in a lens board (Box 73, Folder 3219)
      - Graphic shutter assembly with a Rapid Rectilinear 5 x 7 Bausch & Lomb lens patented January 6, 1891) (Box 73, Folder 3220)
      - EA (probably Edward Anthony manufacturer) Wide Angle 4 with a rotating aperture wheel (Box 73, Folder 3221)
      - Unknown manufacturer with a screw mount and aperture slot (Box 74, Folder 3222)
      - Unknown manufacturer with a screw focus (Box 74, Folder 3223)
      - Voigtländer & Sohn AG, Wien & Braunschweig, No. 1218, with a screw mount, aperture slot, and screw focus (Box 74, Folder 3224)
      - Unknown manufacturer missing mount (Box 75, Folder 3225)
      - Dallmeyer, London, Rapid Rectilinilear 18x16, with an aperture slot (Box 75, Folder 3226)
    - Lens aperture sleeves (Box 75, Folder 3227)
    - Lens mounting screw (Box 75, Folder 3228)
    - Lens mounting screw and board (Box 75, Folder 3229)
    - Mats for printing vignette photographs, (9 mats) (Box 75, Folder 3230)
    - Photographic glass negatives, 4.5 x 10.7 cm. plates, manufactured by the Imperial Dry Plate Company, London, England, sealed package (Box 75, Folder 3231)
    - Photographic glass negative holders for 4.5 x 10.7 cm. plates, manufactured by Elge (Box 75, Folder 3232)
      Three complete negative holders and two sleeves
    - Wratten lens filter X2, manufactured by Eastman Kodak (Box 75, Folder 3233)